COLIN BURGESS

211 N Williamson St, Atlanta, MO 63530 · (719)-351-7456

CRB5825@Gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/c0c0b/

C0C0Barbet.github.io

Experienced in various languages, focused largely on C#, C/C++, and Python. Accomplished at building connections in team settings for improved information flow and production. Excellent communication skills combined with an analytical and attentive nature. Looking forward to problem solving plus developing scalable applications and software.

EDUCATION

MAY 2018

ASSOCIATES OF PSYCHOLOGY, MOBERLY AREA COMMUNITY COLLEGE

DECEMBER 2020

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF ALASKA ANCHORAGE

EXPERIENCE

10/2021 - 01/2022

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

JAVA FULL STACK DEVELOPER

- Hired and began training to become a Java full stack developer on October 11th, 2021.
- The training was completed December 22nd and consisted of Angular and Node.js with a refresher of java, SQL, and JDBC.

01/2022 - 03/2022

STATE OF MISSOURI, OFFICE OF ADMINISTRATION ITSD-DNR

ASSOCIATE APPLICATION DEVELOPER

- Gained advanced professional understanding and coding abilities in Java.
- Developed greater problem-solving skills related to investigation of server issues.
- Supported Missouri's Department of Natural Resources web applications through STRUTS and Spring development.

03/2022 - PRESENT

STATE OF MISSOURI, OFFICE OF ADMINISTRATION ITSD-DNR

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

- Became the lead support on a few java applications where I actively and efficiently implemented bug fixes as well as enhancements.
- Gained a greater understanding of SQL, STRUTS 2, Spring Boot, and Java.
- Mentored newer hires to help acclimate them to the workflow and understand topics they may not be familiar with.
- Took the lead on the WIMS Online Testing expansion resulting in the creation of the DNR Online Testing application.
- Took over responsibility for all .NET applications and oversaw AQS data exchange to the EPA.
- Began training in Azure to start moving some applications into the cloud.

PROJECTS

TOWER OF HANOI REDUX

• While in my senior year of University I enrolled in a computer graphics course which tasked me with creating some application regarding graphics. I eventually decided upon the traditional Tower of Hanoi game which I would build in Unity. After the course had finished, I was left with a rudimentary version of the game and felt compelled to continue my work. Over time I improved the aesthetic and functions of the game leading to what I currently have displayed on my online portfolio. That game is still not as complete as I would like however as I worked on it entirely on my own, I am quite happy! Tower of Hanoi Redux is available on the Google Play Store and is hosted on itch.io.

MY FIRST GAME JAM 2021

• In July of 2021, I was left with free time while job searching and noticed itch.io was hosting a beginner's game jam. I decided to reach out to a friend and try our luck with a simple 2D platformer. The experience was fun and helped me learn how to work in a team and lead as my friend had little experience with Unity. As the game was made in two weeks, forcing me out of my comfort zone. This game is hosted on itch.io and is also available on my online portfolio.

LANGUAGES AND SKILLS

- C# (.NET)
- C++
- Java
- Python
- Django

- HTML, CSS, JSP, JavaScript
- Some Angular/Node.js Training
- Spring Boot
- SQL and DB2

ACTIVITIES

Throughout my post-secondary education, I worked on various projects using the Unity game engine and dabbled in the Unreal engine. In my free time I still like to spend time working on various projects in Unity, Unreal, Java.